Eating outdoors
在户外吃饭
is the essence of camping.
可是露营的醍醐味哦
Even though this is just hot cocoa.
虽然这是热可可就是了
It's lukewarm…
都不烫了
LAID-BACK CAMP SEASON 3
《摇曳露营△ (第三季)》
EPISODE 2: PETIT CAMP AND YARD CAMP
(第2话 小露营和庭院露营)
This won't hold the heat that much longer.
用这个装的话 应该还是一下子就会凉掉了吧
Oh, this is…
这是…
the one Rin used.
小凛用过的那个
It's pretty pricey.
价格还挺贵的
3… 251 yen.
3…251圆
Hmm. Can't afford it.
嗯 买不起
Excuse me.
那个 不好意思
Yes, can I help you?
是 请问怎么了吗
I'd like to heat up my drink.
我想把饮料加热再喝
Do you have any cheaper options?
请问有更便宜的用具吗
Well, in that case…
这样的话…
How about this?
您觉得这个如何呢？
What's this?
这是什么呀？
A pocket stove.
口袋炉
It's so cute and compact.
小小的好可爱
Just put in the solid fuel and light it up.
先放入固态燃料 接着点火
Perfect for a little camping with hot cocoa.
搭配热可可的小露营
It's hot!
好烫
Nothing beats piping hot cocoa.
果然可可就是要喝这么烫的呢
See you next time, Aya!
下次见 小绫
Bye.
再见
Rin,
小凛
when the weather gets a bit warmer,
等天气变暖和一点
I'll come down to Yamanashi.
我也会去山梨玩的
I'll drive a motorcycle,
我要像你那样
just like you.
努力骑机车过去
Motorcycle camping.
机车露营
If it's going on the bike,
如果要放在机车上
it has to be lightweight and compact, right?
就得买轻盈小巧一点的吧
And easy to set up, too.
而且还要能简单搭设
"TENTS FOR MOTORCYCLE CAMPING," Mountain climbing tents?
(适合用于机车露营 登山用帐篷) 登山用的帐篷？
Stuff from the big brands sure is pricey.
知名厂商的东西果然很贵呢
Is there anything cheaper?
有没有再便宜一点的…
"SUPER CHEAP MOUNTAIN CLIMBING" 980 yen?
(超便宜 登山帐篷 户外用圆顶帐篷) 980圆？
What's with the crazy price gap?
这个价格落差是怎么回事
Looks like it'll collapse at the slightest breeze though.
不过感觉马上就会坏掉了
Oh, right.
对了
This one looks pretty decent.
这个好像挺不错的嘛
We're here…
到了…
Welcome, girls!
欢迎你们来
Morning, Ena!
惠那 早安
Morning.
早安
Fresh out of the bed, huh?
是说你还真的是一副 刚起床的打扮呢
A heartfelt reunion.
令人感动的重逢
Chikuwa!
竹轮
It must be cold outside, huh?
外头很冷吧
Sorry.
不好意思
I'll get changed. You girls go ahead and set up the tent.
我马上去换衣服 你们先去搭设吧
Okay!
好
The girls set to work immediately
立刻开始搭设
and completed the task in no time.
迅速完工
All done!
完成
Aoi, a new camping item?
小葵 这是你的新装备吗
"PORTABLE COMPACT TABLE, 4000 YEN" I placed an order.
(小型折叠桌 4000圆) 伊豆露营结束后 我就马上下订单了
I've been looking for a colour that matched my chair.
我从之前就一直在找颜色 和椅子比较搭的桌子了
Nifty and spiffy.
既时尚又好看呢
The surface is fabric,
它的桌面虽然是布
but it's got an aluminium board inside. It looks pretty durable.
不过里面装了铝板 应该满坚固的哦
It sure does.
对吧
White gets dirty easily,
虽然白色系很容易用脏
but I'll do my best to use it with caution.
不过在下定当竭尽所能谨慎使用它
We are in your care.
还请您多多关照
Sorry to keep you guys waiting.
让你们久等了
I'll set up Chikuwa's tent right away.
我现在就来搭帐棚
Wait.
等等
Not yet.
还没好哦
Go ahead!
好
How cute!
好可爱
DOG TENT 10,000 YEN
(犬用帐篷 10000圆)
DOG COT 10,000 YEN
(犬用行军床 10000圆)
DOG SLEEPING BAG 15,000 YEN
(犬用睡袋 15000圆)
CHIKUWA'S CAMPING SET TOTAL: 35,000 YEN
(竹轮用露营套装组 总计35000圆)
Those are some dear prices!
价钱一点都不可爱
Dog camping equipment isn't cheap.
毕竟犬用的东西都不便宜
But if the quality lives up to the price,
不过如果贵 但很耐用
it should last longer.
或许就能用很久了
That's true.
确实
I've only used my super-cheap tent a couple of times,
我的超便宜帐篷明明没用过几次
but the underside's already worn out.
但地板部分已经磨损到快破了
Plus, one of the poles snapped
而且初次试搭时
the first time we tried setting it up.
营柱就啪地断掉了呢
But thanks to that broken pole,
不过 也是因为营柱断掉
we became friends with Rin and Ena.
我们才能跟小凛和惠那变成朋友
When you think about it like that,
这么一想
doesn't it feel like the tent has already paid off big time?
不觉得那个帐篷能用到现在 已经超级回本了吗
Aoi, you said it perfectly!
小葵 你说得太好了
That's so true!
说得太好了
Side note,
顺带一提
it wasn't easy to find a cot that fit inside the tent.
能放进账篷的行军床实在不太好找
I was finally able to get one at a second-hand store.
这是我好不容易 才在中古商店买到的
Sure is a lot of work…
真是层层讲究啊
You are dearly loved, Chikuwa.
你被深爱着呢 竹轮
We're camping in Ena's yard! Woof!
我们要开始在惠那家的 庭院露营咯 汪
Chikuwa in a tent, so cute.
在帐篷里的竹轮 好可爱
Now, then…
接着…
Time to give Aki a haircut.
我们先来帮小明剪头发吧
I'm in your hands.
拜托你咯
So, what kind of hairstyle are we getting today?
那么 你想剪怎样的发型呢？
Well, I was thinking about having the sides and the back cut to about shoulder length.
总之我想先把两侧和后面的 头发剪到肩膀左右
Might as well make it shorter and go for a "cool" look.
再剪短一点 改走帅气风嘛
A cool girl, huh?
帅气风啊
Cool? Something like this?
帅气风的短发 是指这样的吗
No, not that kind of cool!
不是这种意义上的帅法啊
I think a cute style would suit Aki better!
不…我觉得绝对是可爱风比较好
Something fluffy and cute
像这种蓬蓬的可爱发型
would suit Aki perfectly.
感觉很适合小明哦
Cute's not my thing.
我不适合可爱的发型啦
Nah…
算了吧
How about this?
这种感觉吗
No, although it does look cute and fluffy…
不是 虽然它确实又蓬又可爱啦
In that case, let's do the right side cool
那就右半边剪帅气风
and the left side cute.
左半边剪可爱风吧
Please don't.
给我住手
Still, I think there's nothing more Aki than the exposed forehead.
但我还是觉得要露出额头 才有小明的感觉
Original is the best, after all.
结果还是维持原样最适合呢
That's right.
就是说啊
I think the exposed forehead suits Aki the best too.
我也觉得露出额头 比较有小明的感觉
Forget exposed forehead!
别说是露额头了
If you use that thing, my scalp will be showing!
这一推下去 我连头皮都要露出来了
You two, hold her down for me.
你们两个帮我压住她
Wait! Seriously?
等等 真的假的？
No, don't!
不要啊
You're looking fresh.
清爽多了呢
I didn't plan on keeping my hair long,
虽然不是刻意要留长的
but it feels like losing a piece of myself with it cut short.
但一下子剪这么短 总觉得有点寂寞呢
You'll get used to it
用不了多久
in no time.
你就会看习惯短发了啦
I still think it has to be the exposed forehead for Aki.
我还是觉得小明应该露额头
You're still on that?
你还在说啊
Now that Aki's haircut is done,
既然小明也剪好头发了
let's begin the barbecue.
那我们就来烤肉吧
I've been waiting to hear that!
等这一刻很久了
"ALCOHOL FUEL" What kind of sausages
(燃料用酒精) 抚子带了哪种香肠？
"SUPER SPICY CHORIZO" This kind.
(地狱业火 超辣西班牙香肠) 我带了这个
"YAMANASHI PORK, HERB AND LEMON SAUSAGES" I bought this.
(山梨猪 香草柠檬香肠) 我是带这个
"SUPER TASTY CHEESY FISH CAKES" I brought this.
(超好吃 浓郁芝士鱼板) 我的是这个
Does that count as a sausage?
那是香肠吗
"YUMMY CHICKEN BREAST SAUSAGE! YUM! WOOF!" And Chikuwa's favourite.
(超好吃 鸡胸肉香肠 好好吃 汪) 然后 这是竹轮最喜欢的
You like that, Chikuwa?
竹轮 你喜欢吃那个呀
What about you, Aki?
小明带了什么过来？
I brought this!
我带了这个
ON SALE, DOMESTIC GROUND PORK, 398 YEN
(特卖品 国产猪绞肉 398圆)
Ground pork?
这不是绞肉吗
Weren't you the one who said to bring only sausages?
不是你说只能带香肠的吗
Okay. Hold your horses…
好啦 不要着急…
"SAUSAGE CASING" I'm going to use this
(香肠肠衣) 我是要用这个
and this
和这个
to make my own sausages!
自己做香肠
SAUSAGE STUFFER, CASING
(灌香肠机 肠衣) (香肠的外皮)
Homemade sausages? That sounds exciting!
自己做啊 感觉很有趣呢
When did you even get these?
这东西是什么时候买的啊
My mum bought this years ago.
这是我妈好几年前买的
She never used it. It's been left to collect dust.
一直都没有用 都布满灰尘了
Are you sure it's still good?
没问题吧？
Wouldn't it have gone bad by now?
会不会臭酸掉了呀？
I'm not talking about the ground pork!
我不是在说绞肉啦
But are sausages really that easy to make?
不过 香肠真的有那么好做吗
The recipe doesn't seem too difficult.
看食谱上写的内容 应该不会太难哦
Just season the meat with spices and salt,
只要在绞肉里加入香料和盐巴调味 并搅拌均匀
mix well and put it in the sausage stuffer…
再放进这个灌香肠机里
Aoi!
小葵
You can't escape either.
你们也别想逃
You're next.
最后是你
Impressive!
好厉害
It's amazing how well-trained Chikuwa is.
真亏你能把它训练到这种程度耶
That's not all my Chikuwa
我家竹轮的才艺
can do.
可不只有这些哦
Zombie dog?
僵尸狗？
Aki…
小明
Let… Let me go!
住…住手啊
Ena's dad's been watching us all along!
惠那的爸爸一直在盯着我们看耶
Stare…
盯
SHIPPED, IN TRANSIT, OUT FOR DELIVERY
(商品已寄出 配送中 正在运送中)
It's here.
来了
My tent
帐篷
has arrived.
送来了
That was easier than I expected.
比想象中还简单呢
IT'S BEEN A WHILE, RIN.
(小凛 好久不见)
Who's this?
这是谁啊？
SORRY, BUT WHO IS THIS?
(不好意思 请问你是谁？)
OH, SORRY. IT'S AYANO.
(抱歉…我是绫乃啦)
WE MET AT NADESHIKO'S GRANDMA'S HOUSE DURING THE NEW YEAR'S.
(之前新年有在抚子的奶奶家见过)
OH, IT'S YOU, AYA. LONG TIME NO SEE. WHAT'S UP?
(原来是小绫啊) (好久不见 找我有事吗)
I BOUGHT A TENT AND SLEEPING BAG TOO.
(我后来也买了帐篷和睡袋)
THE WEATHER'S TURNED WARM, SO I FIGURED I'D GO ON A CAMPING TRIP WITH MY MOTORCYCLE.
(再加上天气也变暖了) (想说下次要来场机车露营)
WANT TO JOIN ME?
(你要一起去吗)
MOTORCYCLE CAMPING? SOUNDS NICE.
(机车露营啊 不错耶)
HAVE YOU DECIDED WHERE TO GO?
(你决定好要去哪里了吗)
120KM IS QUITE FAR.
(120公里还满远的哦)
SINCE IT'S YOUR FIRST TIME TRAVELLING SO FAR,
(如果是第一次跑长途) (选你家附近的点也可以)
I SUGGEST CHOOSING SOMEWHERE CLOSER TO YOUR HOME.
(小凛平时都骑这么远吧？)
BESIDES, I'LL BE DRIVING. IT'LL BE OKAY.
(而且也不是用自己的脚走) (没问题啦)
ARE YOU SURE?
(真的没问题吗)
THEN, WE'LL CHOOSE SOMEWHERE NEARBY. I'LL GET IN TOUCH AGAIN CLOSER TO THE DATE.
(那我们就去这附近) (等约定的日期快到时 我再跟你连络)
GOT IT. I'LL BE WAITING.
(知道了 那么等你连络)
Though…
不过
LET'S CHOOSE A SPOT HALFWAY BETWEEN WHERE WE LIVE!
(地点就选在我们两家的中间点吧) (差不多120公里)
ABOUT A 120KM DRIVE
没想到小绫还挺随便的呢
What about Nadeshiko?
那抚子该怎么办呢
Welcome.
欢迎光临
Let's get back on track and begin the sausage making.
重整旗鼓 开始制作香肠
First, add spices and salt to the ground meat,
先将香料和盐巴加入绞肉中搅拌 并用手揉到产生粘性为止
Then, add okra, natto, and Egyptian spinach
接着加入秋葵 纳豆 埃及国王菜
to make the meat filling stickier.
让肉馅变得更加粘稠
Don't add random stuff!
别乱加奇怪的东西啊
Then, cut the casing to the required length
接着按照需要的分量剪下肠衣
and slide it onto the metal tube of the sausage stuffer,
并套在灌香肠机的金属管上
tying the front end.
然后把前端绑起来
It looks like shedded snake skin…
好像蛇脱下来的…
Hey, stop right there.
喂 别再继续说下去了
Next, stuff the prepared meat filling into the sausage stuffer.
然后 将揉好的肉馅塞进灌香肠机里
To prevent air from entering the sausages,
为了避免空气跑进香肠里
fill the casing with just the right amount of filling.
要适量地把肉馅灌进去
100% PORK SAUSAGE (UNCOOKED)
(100%猪肉 生香肠)
Once the meat filling is stuffed, tie the back end of the casing.
等灌好肉馅后 将后端绑起来
Then, divide it into sections according to preference, and it's done.
再根据喜欢的长度分节 就完成了
How's that?
怎么样啊
It looks great.
做得还挺有模有样的嘛
That was easy!
这做法真的很简单呢
Right?
对吧
Let's fry them up, Aki.
赶紧来煎煎看吧 小明
Oh, right. Got to set this up first.
对了 还得先放上这个
Huh? Isn't that…
咦 那个不是…
It's the kitchen rack you used as a mini table at the Christmas camp.
是圣诞露营时 当作迷你桌子用的厨房置物架啊
Can't put the frying pan directly on top of the alcohol stove.
因为不能把平底锅 直接放在酒精炉上呀
You really know how to make the most out of that kitchen rack.
你还真会活用这个厨房置物架呢
Well, let's get started.
还好啦 那我要开始咯
As expected, not quite enough fire.
火力果然不太够呢
Let's dump the meat in.
先把肉放进去好了
That's too many…
放太多了…
It's sizzling!
开始闻到香味了
Even though we're just frying some sausages
用这个铸铁锅煎东西
with the skillets, this is pretty nice.
就算只是煎香肠也很有气氛呢
Uh-huh.
就是说啊
I've washed and seasoned them with olive oil.
而且这个锅子我洗了很多次 还上了很多次橄榄油
Stuff don't stick or burn easily anymore.
现在已经变得越来越不容易烤焦
They're great to use.
还挺不错的哦
You're a "well-seasoned" chef with how much care you put into your wares.
细心培育厨具什么的 感觉很有大师的风范呢
Aki, I think they're done.
明 好像已经煎好咯
Oh, you're right.
对耶
Aki, can I try one now?
小明 我可以吃一根吗
Get them while they're hot!
赶紧趁热吃吧
Time to dig in!
我要开动了
The herb sausage is done.
香草香肠已经好了哦
The chorizo needs a little more time.
西班牙香肠还要再煎一下呢
At least say something about it! You guys are scaring me…
你们说点什么啊 这样很可怕耶
Um, well…
呃 这个嘛
You should try one too.
你也先吃一口看看吧
The chorizo has a nice spicy kick to it!
西班牙香肠辣辣的真好吃
She's using the chorizo as a palate cleanser!
居然拿西班牙香肠盖味道
I mean, it's not that bad…
哎呀 其实也不到难以下咽的程度啦
Could use a little more fat…
但就是油脂有点不够
Tastes rustic.
有种手工制作的粗糙感
Don't bother sugarcoating anything. It's disgusting.
老实说 真的超难吃的
Exactly, Aki.
小明 你说出我们的心声了
Why?
为什么会这样
It was such a simple recipe! Where did I go wrong?
做法明明很简单 不可能会失败吧
Aki, look at this.
小明 你看这个
Take note!
注意
The ground meat must be kept in the freezer before use.
在开始料理前 绞肉一定要冰在冷藏里
The same goes for the sausage stuffer and the mixing bowl.
灌香肠机和搅拌盆 也要事先冰进冷冻库里
When preparing the meat mixture,
在调制肉馅时
to prevent the ground meat from being affected by the temperature of the hand,
为了避免绞肉受到手的温度影响
please add crushed ice to the processor
请倒入刨冰状的碎冰 用搅拌机一起搅拌
to keep the temperature low.
让肉馅保持在低温状态
It says that if the temperature of the meat is too high,
上面说肉的温度一旦过高
the lean and fatty parts won't mix well,
瘦肉和油脂就无法均匀混合
and the stuffing will dry out.
肉质也会变得干巴巴的
So, that's why…
原来是这样啊
The steps are simple,
做法看似简单
but it's strict on temperature control.
其实对温控有着严格的要求呢
I don't want to waste all that meat.
这样太浪费了
I'll bring it home and make some minced meat out of it.
我还是带回家重新料理 剁成肉末吃吧
Don't beat yourself up over it, Aki.
别难过 小明
Are you comforting me, Chikuwa?
你…是来安慰我的吗
Eh?
咦
"LEASH" Oh, you just wanted to go on a walk.
(牵绳) 原来只是想去散步吗
Let's go on a walk, then.
那我们就去散步一下吧
Bring the chairs too.
大家把椅子带上
Chairs?
椅子？
This place is swell.
这里真不错呢
Makes me wish we had some manjus.
这景色让人忍不住想吃馒头呢
Our DIY alcohol stoves came in handier than I expected.
幸好自制的酒精炉 比想象中还好用呢
Yeah, using the stuff you made by yourself is pretty nice.
自己做装备或许也挺不错的
Aki, any other things we can DIY?
小明 还有其他可以自己做的东西吗
How about we make some leather crafts?
不然来试试皮革手工艺吧
We can use them as covers for the cooking gas cans and bags.
可以用皮革做瓦斯罐套 或杂物收纳袋哦
Good idea. Sounds stylish.
不错耶 有种时尚露营者的感觉
And
还有
we can carve chopsticks and spoons out of wood.
也能用木材削成筷子或汤匙之类的
Great idea!
好主意
That could come in handy in a situation…
如果能当场做出那种小东西
I forgot the chopsticks.
忘记带筷子了
Leave it to me!
交给我吧
There we go, Rin!
我做好咯 小凛
Amazing.
好厉害
It'd be so cool if we could do that.
肯定会很帅吧
You smell so nice, Chikuwa.
竹轮身上好像有股香香的味道呢
It's cherry blossom season soon.
再过不久樱花就要开了
Should we go flower viewing together?
大家要不要一起去赏花？
That sounds nice.
不错耶
I'm in!
赞成
An outdoor activities club flower viewing camp!
我想要办个符合 野外活动同好会风格的赏花露营
A flower viewing camp sounds neat.
赏花露营 感觉不错呢
Are there any campsites around here suitable for flower viewing?
这附近有可以赏樱的露营场吗
There are cherry blossoms around Lake Shibire and Lake Tanuki.
四尾连湖和田贯湖那边应该有樱花
But it won't be a pleasant camping trip
可是 如果跑去赏花露营
if everyone else had the same idea
结果现场却人满为患
and we all end up
周遭都是在开宴会的人
at an overcrowded lake.
那可就麻烦了啊
True.
确实
Find a hidden gem where we can enjoy the cherry blossoms in peace
不是去找一个可以 安静赏花露营的秘境
or just go flower viewing,
就是只能单纯去赏花
we'll have to choose.
要选哪个才好呢
What do you think, Chikuwa?
竹轮觉得呢？
Take care on your way back, everybody.
那么 大家路上小心哦
Bye.
再见
See you again soon, Chikuwa.
竹轮也下次再见咯
"HEATED FLOORING" The house has heated flooring.
(地暖) 家里有地暖
Chikuwa's already asleep.
竹轮已经睡着了呢
He's been completely domesticated.
完全失去野性了啊
Bye!
掰掰
The days are getting longer.
最近 白天好像越来越长了呢
It's almost spring.
毕竟也快到春天了啊
Yeah.
是啊
Bye, you two.
再见啦 两位
See you.
再见
SOLO, BOUND FOR KOFU
(单人乘务 往甲府)
I went to Izu with everyone
不仅和大家一起去伊豆露营
and had my first yard camp today.
今天还尝试了庭院露营
Maybe I should go solo camping again?
下次要不要去单人露营呢
It's time for a solo camp.
是时候该来场单人露营了呢
It's Aya.
是小绫传来的
NADESHIKO, YOU, ME, AND RIN! LET'S GO CAMPING TOGETHER!
(抚子 和我跟小凛三个人一起去露营吧)
IN OIGAWA!
(去大井川)
Oigawa?
大井川？
Good work today.
您辛苦了
I'm down for the Oigawa camp!
大井川露营 没问题
Okay.
哦
Great.
太好了
But why Oigawa?
但是 为什么会选大井川呀？
It'd be difficult if we chose a location
如果没选在两家的中间点
that wasn't somewhere midpoint.
其中一个人不是会很辛苦吗
So, I did some research
然后我查了一下
and found out that Oikawa happened to be somewhere in between.
发现我们两家的中间点 正好在大井川附近
We're planning to drive around Oigawa first
第一天我们打算骑车 到井川附近逛逛
before heading to the campsite.
接着再去露营场
You'll be on your own until then, is that okay?
在那之前你可能要单独行动 没问题吗
No problem…
没问题…
I was just thinking about going on a solo camp.
刚才正想说差不多该去单人露营了
I'll enjoy it as a solo camp.
我会当作单人露营好好享受的
So, solo camp.
差不多该去单人单人露营
So, solo camp solo.
差不多该去单人单人单人露营
And I'll be bringing that hamburg steak.
还有 我会买那个汉堡排过去的
Look forward to it.
敬请期待
Really? Yay!
真的吗 太好了
Hamburg steak?
那个汉堡排？
I'm back.
我回来了
NEXT EPISODE: BRIDGE COUNTRY
(下集 前往吊桥之国)
WHEN ENJOYING CAMPING, BE SURE TO FOLLOW THE RULES
(享受露营时…) (务必遵守露营场和其设施的规定)
DON'T FORGET TO PUT OUT YOUR CAMPFIRE AND DISPOSE OF YOUR GARBAGE.
(别忘了灭火和带走垃圾)
TEMPERATURES CAN CHANGE QUICKLY, SO CHECK THE WEATHER FORECAST BEFOREHAND.
(由于气温可能会急速变化) (记得事先确认天气预报)
WEAR WARM CLOTHING IF NECESSARY TO PREVENT COLD.
(必要时穿着保暖衣物防寒)